NWANU, NDUBUISI MARTINS

26 Femi-adebule Street, Folagoro, Shomolu, Lagos. Mobile No: 08164755717, 08021262475

Email: nwanumartins@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Head, Software Engineer with over 6 years of experience in the IT industry with strength in developing APIs and web applications using the following programming languages: Java (spring framework) and JavaScript. It's worth mentioning that I also have experience in application support and managing applications plus creating use cases and test cases for overall application quality assurance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manager, Software Engineer, January 2022 – Current

Creditville Limited- Lagos, Nigeria

Responsibilities/Accomplishments:

- Handling of proper UAT and go-live process
- Handling of support of creditville savings and loans mobile application (C Money) version 1.0
- Review and guidance of Creditville new application development process
- Setting up and improvement of software engineers that manages all the Creditville subsidiary such as website development, application development and system support.
- Supporting of all existing applications (such as credit check report, bulk payment upload).
- Managing / development of Creditville (Touchgold MFB) mobile banking application (C Money) version 2.0
- Supervising and development of Creditville portal system (Ongoing project)
- Supervising and development of C Money web application. (Ongoing project)
- Supervising and development of Touchgold MFB, (one of Creditville Limited subsidiary) website (Ongoing project).

Manager, Information Technology, August 2020 – January 2022

Creditville Limited- Lagos, Nigeria

Responsibilities/Accomplishments:

- Setting up and improvement of the IT department that manages all the Creditville subsidiary such as Network infrastructure, improve mail system, website development, application development and system support
- Supported all existing java applications (such as credit check report, bulk

- payment upload).
- Collaboration with Instafin engineer teams to enhance the core banking application to meet the business need.
- Management of the external vendor such as paystack engineering team, flutterwave engineering team, Remita engineering team, Instafin engineering team, Opay engineering team, interswitch (Vanso) engineering team, Lendsqr engineering team (mobile). ensuring that their services are rendered in accordance with business need.
- Manage Creditville core banking application (INSTAFIN)
- Management and development of Creditville (Touchgold MFB) mobile banking application (C Money)
- Manage all IT infrastructures with the team.
- Management and automation of business processes.
- Management and development of java application for loan repayment. Using these channels (Remita, Paystack, Flutterwave, Opay) with the development team
- Developed java application that generate transaction report for collections unit
- Developed loan disbarment application (Flutterwave, Remita, Opay, Paystack)

Senior Software Engineer, December 2018 – August 2020

Renmoney MFB - Lagos, Nigeria

Responsibilities/Accomplishments:

- Supported all existing java application (Gds-fast-track, credit check report, bulk payment upload, pay out).
- Developed Node JS application that process bank statement.
- Developed Java API (REST) that encrypt and decrypt request / response for NIBBS transaction.
- Developed Java application that send out settlement sheet (offer letter) to clients.
- Developed Java application, my bank statement (MBS), App that get client last six months bank statement, loop through the bank statement narration for keywords set by the admin in the database, process, save, update necessary field and notified data science team for decision making.
- Developed java application that sends repayment schedule notification to clients via email and sms.
- Developed java application and API that generate renmoney bank statement.
- Developed an API that returns Paystack link for payment.
- Developed java API for BVN verification.
- Developed an API for funds transfer, name enquire and transaction verification.
- Developed java application for under-writer team for decision making.
- Developed java API for intra bank transfer.
- Developed java API for ID (Voters card, BVN, Driver's license etc) verification.
- Developed java API that generate renmoney account number (using CBN algorithm).
- Currently developing an APIs for renmoney mobile and web app.

Head of Support and Quality Assurance, July 2017 – December 2018

Longbridge Technologies Ltd. - Lagos, Nigeria

Responsibilities/Accomplishments:

- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality and function before it will be release.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance
- Collaborate with product management team to design, build and test applications.
- Worked effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions met client expectation.
- Interfaced with business analysts, other developers and technical support teams to determine the best requirements to meet satisfactory customer experience for solutions.

Software Engineer, September 2015 – July 2017

Longbridge Technologies Ltd. – Lagos, Nigeria

Responsibilities/Accomplishments:

- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions in a timely manner.
- Designed and developed help desk application for support unit
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interface and improve performance

Site Surveyor, August 2014 – July 2015

Ministry of Land and Survey – Makurdi, Benue State,

Nigeria. (NYSC Place of Primary Assignment)

Responsibilities:

- Create assembly and layout drawings using AutoCAD 2007.
- Carryout topographic survey
- Prepared plans and layouts for equipment / system arrangements and space allocation

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Hands-on use of the following:

- Java
- Spring framework, Spring boot, Java EE
- JavaScript
- Node JS
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JQuery & AJAX
- Git

- MySQL
- Linux and Windows Server Management and Deployment
- Hibernate
- AutoCAD
- Microsoft office packages

EDUCATION

2011 – 2013 : **Yaba collage of Technology**, Yaba,

Lagos - HND, Surveying and Geo-

informatics.

2008 – 2010 : **Yaba collage of Technology**, Yaba,

Lagos - OND, Surveying and Geo-

informatics.

1999 – 2005 : Shalom Gate Secondary School,

Oyigbo, Rivers State.

Senior School Certificate Examination.

1994 – 1999 : **Rosy Law International Primary**

school, Aba, Abia State.

First School Leaving Certificate

KEY FEATURES

- Resourceful team player with excellent leadership skills.
- Strong desire to learn and expand skill set especially in areas of software technology.
- Ability to thrive in dynamic fast paced business environments.
- Ability to independently prioritize multiple tasks and work efficiently to meet deadlines.
- Flexible, adaptable, and open to change.
- Strong analytical skills with excellent problem-solving abilities.
- Emotional intelligence and time management skills.
- Self-confident with good relationship skills.